Contact

time2goride@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/jo-ann-evans-b9a15366 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Nursing

Surgery

Medical Terminology

Languages

conversational Italian

Certifications

CCRN

Advanced Cardiovascular Life Support Experienced Provider (ACLS)

Jo Ann Evans

AGACNP, MS, BSN, CCRN, CPTC

Williamsport, Pennsylvania Area

Summary

AGACNP-BC, nurse manager/care coordinator with fifteen years critical care experience across the lifespan. Seven years experience as Procurement Transplant Coordinator, in busy OPO. Have taught BCLS/ACLS/PALS. Nurse educator for both BSN and LPN programs. Rapid response/code team leader. Skilled at teaching, motivating, and empowering multidisciplinary staff to achieve highest possible quality of care.

Experience

UPMC Susquehanna
Acute Care Nurse Practitioner
October 2019 - Present (10 months)
United States

Nevada Donor Network
Procurement Transplant Coordinator III
August 2014 - April 2017 (2 years 9 months)
Las Vegas, Nevada Area

Susquehanna Health Clinical Supervisor/Resource Nurse - Critical Care Unit December 2011 - August 2014 (2 years 9 months) Williamsport Area, Pennsylvania

Direct management of ICU, CVSU and progressive care units; Rapid response team leader; staff education and competency training; compliance; quality assurance; EBM

Pennsylvania College of Technology Faculty Member March 2010 - August 2014 (4 years 6 months) Williamsport, Pennsylvania

Part time faculty member for Bachelor's and Associates degree programs in School of Nursing.

Gift of Life Donor Program

Procurement Transplant Coordinator
February 2005 - February 2012 (7 years 1 month)

Philadelphia, Pennsylvania

Coordinate all aspects of organ/tissue donation cases; consistently exceeded dashboard expectations to maximize recipient outcomes via critical thinking, clinical expertise, and collaboration; assisted in development of clinical training program; educate and encourage peers and orientees as a preceptor and mentor.

Crozer Keystone Health System
Evidence Based Medicine Project Coordinator
June 2002 - February 2006 (3 years 9 months)

Designed project to develop and implement Evidence Based Medicine best practices utilizing multidisciplinary team to drastically reduce VAP, readmission and mortality rates, and ensure highest quality of care in critical care arenas.

UPMC

Critical Care Registered Nurse January 1998 - June 2002 (4 years 6 months) University of Pittsburgh Medical Center - Presbyterian Campus

CCRN/charge RN in adult multivisceral transplant ICU. Charge RN in pediatric surgical acute care unit.

Education

University of Colorado Denver
MSN, Adult Acute Care Nurse Practitioner · (2017 - 2019)

Duquesne University
Bachelor of Science (BS), Registered Nursing/Registered
Nurse · (1998 - 2000)

Penn State University
Bachelor of Science (BS), Biological and Physical Sciences/
psychology · (1987 - 1991)